Web-230 | How PHP Works - Server Side Scripting Assignment

1) Identify and explain the differences between server side and client side.
	 
	➥ The differences between server side and client side are how the scripting language is run - client side using a browser and server side using a web server. The process of script running on the client side takes place on the users computer while the script is run directly on the web server to create HTML pages that are sent to the client browser.


2) Identify and explain the differences between scripting and programming languages.
	
	➥ The difference between scripting and programming languages is that programming needs to be compiled while scripting does not. Programming languages also run faster since compilers read and analyze code once but the interpreter read and analyze code each time but stops if there's an error. 


3) Explain what type of language PHP is.

	➥ PHP is a server scripting language used for web development and as a general use programming language. PHP can be used in HTML/HTML5 or other web template systems, content management systems and frameworks. 


4) Explain the process of a request from client to server and back to client.

	➥ First, the client makes a file request to the server, the server gets the file and the file is sent back. File is usually an html file and it tells the server what kind of file it is. 


5) Explain the differences between the different post types discussed in the video.

	➥ HTTP Post are query strings that are send in the HTTP message body. PostBack is when infomation is sent to the server with newer information than the first time, it's going to do something differently with it than it did with the first file. 